# **Elaine Lagon**

Fort Worth, TX 76123 | 817-480-3431 | emlportfolio@gmail.com

**GitHub**: <a href="https://github.com/elaine-drum-female">https://github.com/elaine-drum-female</a> **LinkedIn**: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/elagonwork/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/elagonwork/</a>

Portfolio: <a href="https://elaine-drum-female.github.io/new-portfolio-site/">https://elaine-drum-female.github.io/new-portfolio-site/</a>

## **SUMMARY**

Front-End Developer with extensive web development experience updating and maintaining internal and external websites using content management systems for in-house companies. Graduated Summa Cum Laude and holds a Bachelor of Science in Multimedia Design and Web Development. My strongest skills are design and usability.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript/jQuery, Git, GitHub, Responsive Design, Twitter Bootstrap
- Wireframing, Firebase, Client-Side-Storage, Adobe Creative Cloud Products
- Node.js, MySQL and Sequelize, Mongoose, Express, Handlebars, React, AJAX, APIs

## **PROJECTS**

Bootstrap Portfolio | Github Repository | My Bootstrap Portfolio

The goal of this project was to create a portfolio website using Bootstrap's framework.

Role: Sole Developer

• HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

RPG Game | Github Repository | RPG Game

Endless fighting between user created characters.

Role: Front-End Developer

• HTML, CSS, AJAX Request, APIs, jQuery

## BamazonCustomer | Github Repository

Create an Amazon-like storefront with the MySQL skills you learned this unit. The app will take in orders from customers and deplete stock from the store's inventory.

Role: Sole Developer

• ¡Query, MySQL, Inquirer, Node.js

## RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **WEB DESIGNER**

**JANUARY 2017 - AUGUST 2018** 

The Insource Group, Inc., Dallas, TX

# Client: First Command Financial Services, Inc., Fort Worth, TX

- Redesigned specific sections of web content to be inline with mobile first design
- Generated an inventory list of less than 500 webpage links from both public websites and delivered final product in less than a week within a 2-3-week deadline
- Assisted the Marketing Insights Manager by writing out HTML code for a simple template used to help visualize survey collection concept, and imagery prior to sending out to Advisors

## Digital Alchemy, Inc., Fort Worth, TX

- Recommended the best designer in-house by assigned clients and supervisor
- Produced a quick mockup for client and was approved same day
- Implemented an idea to the CEO to help speed up process of building a comment card
- Launched from start to finish 25+ email templates per month

### WEB DEVELOPER / WEB DESIGNER INTERN

OCTOBER 2013- JANUARY 2014

Nautilus Hyosung America, Inc., Irving, TX

- Designed and coded a 30 second advertisement banner at 18fps within 48 hours
- Devised a new idea for our tagline

## ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

## TRAINING DEVELOPMENT ASSISTANT

SEPTEMBER 2015 - DECEMBER 2016

Shermco Industries, Inc., Irving, TX

- Developed Shermco U Resource Catalog less than a month with 50% done in two days
- Brainstormed and implemented the Shermco U flyer and produced draft on same day

### **CLERICAL ASSISTANT**

JANUARY 2008- APRIL 2013

# AXA-ADVISORS, Fort Worth, TX

- Entered 100 clients into the address book in one day
- Handled large file stack of client folders in less than a week
- Copied and compiled large stacks of Commission Statements to be mailed out on the same day

### **EDUCATION**

**NOVEMBER 2018** 

Web Development Certification

SMU, TX

Bachelor of Science in Multimedia Design and Web Development

Summa Cum Laude

**DeVry University, Irving, TX** 

Associates of Applied Science in Information Technology

Tarrant County College, Fort Worth, TX

# **AWARDS**

Certificate in Creating Web Pages

LoneStar College, Conroe, TX

Certificate in Creating Web Graphics

LoneStar College, Conroe, TX